[MICHE] The odds of there being
any Titans
in the hundred and forth
Cadet Corps are low.
We've got multiple Titans
incoming from the south!
Wall Rose has been compromised!
[NARRATOR] Suspected by some
of unknowingly harboring
the enemy among their ranks,
the hundred and fourth Cadet
Corps was kept isolated.
With the sudden emergence
of a Titan swarm,
couriers were dispatched to
alert surrounding districts.
[NANABA]
As you have guessed,
today marks the darkest hour
in humanity's history!
Don't lose heart.
If ever we needed
to give our all,
that time is now!
Look sharp!
[NARRATOR]
However...
[BOTH gasp]
[MICHE] No! They're
coming at us full tilt!
[HORSE 26A whinnies]
[NARRATOR] Their origins
and how they got here
remain a mystery.
Mankind is still in the dark.
[Yells]
[MICHE screams]
Ah, an exceptionally
clever idea, I must say.
[Screams]
♪ Opening Song  ♪
[MALE MESSENGER 27A]
Commander Pyxis!
[Panting]
Titans have been spotted, sir!
We think Wall Rose
has been breached!
[PYXIS growls lowly]
[HORSE neighs]
[EREN] Great. Somebody explain
to me what this means.
[ARMIN] I don't know.
But they're Titans, right?
Would they break a wall
with Titans in it?
Wouldn't be the first time.
It's how they
got into Shiganshina.
[ARMIN]
That was a gate.
Armin. What exactly
are you getting at?
[MALE SOLDIER 27B]
Fall in!
[ARMIN]
The walls are different.
There are no signs
of stress, no cracks,
no crevices between the rocks.
We can't even really tell
how they were constructed.
Suppose they're built
with the same stuff
Annie's trapped herself in?
[BOTH gasp]
Must be versatile material,
and we know it's virtually
indestructible.
So the walls
are made of Titans?
Section Commander!
Why are you taking so long?
Please! They're leaving in five
minutes with or without us!
You've got to wrap it up!
Hold your horses,
I just need another moment.
[Gasps]
[LEVI]
Hange. Get moving.
[HANGE] Uh, right!
Sorry! And our guest?
He's been ready
to go for a while.
[HORSE neighs]
[MIKASA] Eren, you'll
get cold. Wear it tight.
[HANGE]
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Took longer to prepare
than I thought.
[Gasps]
He's, uh. He's a priest
from the Order of the Walls.
I know! Ol' Nick and me
are thick as thieves!
[Laughs]
It's fine. Makes about
as much sense for him
to be here as the rest
of us, don't'cha think?
We're random.
No, on the contrary.
Erwin's thrown us
together for a reason.
[MALE SOLDIER 27B]
Open the gate!
[HORSE neighs]
The status
of Wall Rose in unclear,
but everything
up to Ehrmich is safe.
That's the route
we'll be taking.
Let's move out!
[SOLDIERS]
Yes, sir!
You heard 'im.
[MOBLIT]
Sir!
[ARMIN] This whole time,
Titans have been
protecting us from other Titans.
[EREN]
Wait, wait! Back up!
You're joking, right?
This guy knew?
He knew and he kept quiet?
Uh-huh. Afraid so.
Just about sums up
where we are with him.
[Exhales]
[HANGE] Cat's out of
the bag now, of course.
He's not willing to talk yet,
but we'll see how he feels
after a harsh dose of reality.
Faith keeps him quiet.
Firsthand experience, though?
[EREN]
To hell with that!
No! We're doing this backwards!
If this son of bitch
knows something
he needs to come out with it!
Humanity's on
the brink of extinction
and all you care about
is keeping your oath?
[MIKASA]
Hey. Take it easy.
You're still not
fully recovered.
[LEVI] There's more than
one way to get at the truth.
Granted I may not be
in top form at the moment,
but it doesn't take much
strength to squeeze a trigger.
That said. I'm genuinely
hoping I won't have to
blow a hole in you
to settle this.
How about you?
[HANGE] Threatening him
doesn't work, Levi.
Trust me on that.
Agree with him or not,
there's no denying
our priest here
is a man of principle.
Which of course
leads me to wonder:
if he's so unwilling to talk,
what in heaven's name
do you imagine he's putting
above the fate of humanity?
[SASHA] Up ahead, you see?
That's the village!
[MALE SOLDIER 26G]
Where you're from?
[SASHA] No, but it's close.
My people live the forest.
It's okay. Go on.
All right. Find your home
and raise the alarm.
[SASHA]
Yes, sir!
[HORSE neighs]
[SASHA'S FATHER] Good lord!
Again with this?
Sasha! You can't always
be stuffin' your face!
Give it here!
Spit it out!
We're smoking that
for the winter!
Oh, for cryin' out loud!
[Yells]
You little--
Show some restraint!
[SASHA'S FATHER grunts]
Fine.
Eat your fill.
Hm! Idiot kid.
[SASHA'S FATHER sighs]
Sasha. Look around ya.
Ever wonder how things
got to be the way they are?
Why the forest is disappearing?
Why game's so hard
to come by these days?
Or doesn't it concern you?
Sure it does.
People are comin' in here
and helping themselves
to what used to be ours.
It's why I'm hungry
all the time.
Yeah, that's true.
On the face of it.
But where else
you expect folks to go
when they lose their homes?
They've got a right
to live, don't they?
It's their fault
for losing their homes.
Not like that gives 'em
the right to steal.
They lost their homes
'cause of Titans.
Monsters punched a hole
clean through Wall Maria.
Where else were
people gonna go?
Wasn't their choice.
They had to survive somehow,
so they cleared the forest
and used it for farmland.
Maybe it's time
for us to let go.
Surrender the old ways.
We're not gonna starve.
Government's willing
to pay us, y'know.
We'll make money raising horses.
[SASHA gasps] What? If we
turn our back on hunting,
we turn our back on who we are!
Why should I care about
what happens to the people
who've always looked down as us
like we were a bunch of savages?
I'll tell you why.
We're in this together.
The world belongs to each
and every one of us.
We're human.
Humans are social animals.
It's all fine
and good to move to
the beat of your own drum,
but when land is scarce,
you've got to fall
in step with the herd.
Think about the greater good.
[SASHA]
No! I won't do it!
We've lived here all our lives
the way our ancestors
taught us to.
I'm not gonna change!
Screw the "greater good"!
What about us?
Right, then.
If that's how you really feel.
[Inhales]
Eke out a living
in these woods.
Live by the old ways,
like the others.
But I'll tell you something,
you'd best be willing to
die by the old ways, too.
[Gasps]
[SASHA'S FATHER]
'Cause make no mistake, Sasha,
trouble is coming
sooner or later.
And when it does,
there'll be
no begging for help
from the people
you've turned your back on.
If it means
the difference between
being a part of something
larger than myself
and scraping by on my own,
I say screw tradition.
It's time to move on.
What about you?
Are you brave enough
to take that step with me?
Trade the wilderness
of your ancestors
for a share in civilization?
Or is our fellow man
just not worth the hassle?
[SASHA] How long
has it been? Three years?
Surely he'd have had the sense
to pick up and leave by now.
Impossible!
All the way out here?
Can they really
have gotten this far?
That's does it.
This place isn't safe anymore.
[Gasps]
[SASHA] Whoa.
When did that get built?
[TITAN 27A chews]
[Squelching]
[FEMALE VILLAGER 27A
breathes slowly]
[Chirps]
[FEMALE VILLAGER 27A
gasps and groans]
[Music plays,
volume increases]
[SASHA bellows]
[SASHA grunts]
[SASHA] Shit!
If I don't cut it off,
it'll just keep healing!
[Gasps]
[Hollers]
[FEMALE VILLAGER 27A groans]
Oh no.
[FEMALE VILLAGER 27A gasps]
I'm so sorry. Forgive me.
[Gasps]
You got a name, sweetie?
I know you're scared,
but it'll be okay.
[GIRL 27A]
What will?
Uh. Well, um,
actually, I, uh...
Uh, easy now, easy.
Right, so.
The thing is,
I'm going to take you--
[Screams]
You do this now? Really?
Ugh! Wait for us!
[Whistles]
Okay. No need
to worry, understand?
He'll be right back, I promise.
How come you're talking
so nice to me?
Huh?
[Shrieks]
[SASHA]
We need to run!
[Panting]
It's gonna be okay!
No it won't.
Everyone's already gone.
The whole village.
Even though
Mama's legs were bad.
They knew, and none
of them came to help her.
All I could do was watch.
--[Crash]
--[SASHA yells]
Don't look back!
Just keep running!
It's gonna be okay.
[YMIR] You're startin'
to piss me off.
Huh?
[YMIR] Why you gotta be so
friggin' polite all the time?
[Chuckles nervously]
What, you above talking
like one of us plebes?
Well, actually.
No, not at all.
Oh yeah?
So why don't'cha, then?
Scared we'll hear
where you're from
if you let your guard down?
That's it, isn't it?
Oh, wow.
Kinda blows my mind.
Why do you even care?
I mean, it's like a wild boar
getting all bent outta shape
'cause someone's bad-mouthing
him behind his back.
Be honest: the military's
your last hope
of being respectable.
Your folks're probably
first cousins--
Ymir, stop it!
You're being mean!
Whatever! Hey,
you gonna pretend to be
someone you're not for
the rest of your damn life,
or you gonna be Sasha?
Take it from me, honey:
acting like you think
people want you to act
is a crock of shit.
Don't censor yourself!
Um. Thank you very much?
I appreciate the advice.
Really?
[SASHA] Sorry, I-I'm not
really sure what to say.
Leave her alone!
It's her life!
If she wants to talk politely
to people, why doyoucare?
Sasha is who she
chooses to be.
It's called
reinventing yourself.
Whatever she says,
it's still her.
Heh. Well, aren't
we philosophical.
I say however she tries
to sound on the outside,
the inside Sasha'll always
be a pain in the ass.
Knock it off!
Would it kill you
to show some compassion
every now and again?
[YMIR] E-Excuse me?
I'm just bein' real!
--[YMIR] Compassion.
--[SASHA laughs]
[YMIR] Hey!
What are you laughing at?
[SASHA]
Uh. Nothing! Sorry!
[SASHA] Really? Why is
that coming back now?
Of all the stupid things
for me to dwell on.
Still, it's the only thing
I can think about.
[SASHA]
All right, listen.
You're gonna be fine.
Just keep following
the path we're on.
Run as far away as you can.
There'll be someone
willing to help. I promise.
It may take you
a little while to find them.
But keep on! You'll bump
into them eventually!
Now go. Get out of here!
Don't give up hope!
[Panting]
[SASHA]
If I can take out the eyes,
it should buy us enough time.
Eeh!
Damn it. Only two left!
Relax. It's nothing.
Just a big...
slow-moving...
...target!
Bull's eye!
Last arrow.
If I miss, that'll be it.
End of story.
Period. I'll be...
She'll be...
[SASHA bellows]
[TITAN 27A groans]
[SASHA grunts]
[SASHA] I slipped out
because of the blood.
Now to find the girl!
[Panting]
[SASHA gasps]
Is that Sasha?
[SASHA'S FATHER] We've been
doing what we can.
Giving horses
to folks who need 'em.
That little girl
told us there was someone
back behind her on the road.
Said they helped.
Saved her, 'n fact.
Apparently fought off
a Titan single-handed.
[SASHA]
Mm.
Nicely done.
I'm proud of ya.
[Gasps]
Thanks, Dad.
It's good to be home.
Conny, slow down!
Get ahold of yourself!
There could be Titans
around every corner!
Wait for us!
This isn't real.
Hello? Can anybody hear me?
Somebody! Please!
It's Conny!
I came home!
Find my house!
[CONNY] Dad. Mom.
Sunny and Martin!
Please just be okay.
[Gasps]
[HORSE whinnies]
[Breathes quaveringly]
What are you doing?
Get back!
But it, it's my house.
I...
Conny.
Cadets, fall back!
[FEMALE SOLDIER 26B]
I'll scout out the area!
What the hell?
This is new.
Can it move?
[FEMALE SOLDIER 26B]
Not with those legs.
[GELGAR]
But... then...
I don't understand.
How did it even get here?
♪ Closing Song ♪